Melle Dijkstra

Software Engineer Student

Application Developer • Computer Scientist

Wilgenlaan 12, Dokkum, 9103 SC The Netherlands (Phone and email deliberately left out of public resume) → LinkedIn

Profile

Experienced **Software Engineer** with 5 years of demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Currently in the 4th year of study with diverse **hard** and **soft** skills developed through various projects, internships and working experience. Professional proficiency in the English language needed for a business environment. Ambitious and **motivated** young professional with previous **technical experience** and someone that is eager to **learn anything** in order to solve problems of any size. Personal tagline: "ICT for development & social good".

Education

Software Engineering | Hanze University of Applied Sciences

BSc. Computer and Information Sciences, Bachelor of Science September 2016 - June 2020 (Anticipated), Groningen, The Netherlands

<u>Courses:</u> Algorithms & Data Structures, Network Infrastructures, Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning, Website Development, Project Development, IT Service Management & Security, Data Analysis & Visualization

Exchange Student | CEU San Pablo

Februari 2019 - June 2019, Madrid, Spain

<u>Courses:</u> Fundamentals of Marketing, Business Management and Organization II, Economic Theory II, Spanish Beginner Course

• Application & Media Developer | MBO ROC Friese Poort

September 2014 - June 2016, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

<u>Courses:</u> Design of Applications, Realization & Documenting Applications, Implementing Applications, Maintaining Applications, Operating Systems

Experience

Application Developer | <u>Bouw7</u>

December 2015 - Present, Dokkum, The Netherlands

Bouw7 creates cloud-based software solutions for construction companies. Currently, I work on the creation of the web application, provide data analysis & visualization and create 3D solutions with Autodesk software.

Tasks include:

- Backend PHP development (with Symfony & Yii2 Framework)
- Frontend Development (HTML, Javascript & CSS)
- Continuous Integration & Development
- Server Management & Programming Environment (Linux systems & Docker)
- Autodesk Forge 3D Development
- Data Analysis & Visualization (Tableau, Google Analytics)

Intern Application Developer | Stroetenga Design

February 2016 - June 2016, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

The internship consisted of developing a customer portal with Zend Framework 2. Also working in a team, planning and progression evaluation every week.

Task included:

- Team Management
- Planning and weekly progression evaluation

Engineering Intern | National Instructors College Abilonino

September 2018 - Januari 2019, Lira, Uganda

Challenging internship where one had to take into account that there is little to no internet accessibility. The main objective of the internship was on-premise (intranet) access to course material, school calendar and shared files for staff and students and productivity improvement in administration.

Task included:

- Teaching programming skills to students
- Setting up two offline systems (Learning Management System & Management Information System)
- On-premise file sharing environment (Windows Server)
- Improving, regulating and monitoring the internet & intranet usage

· Intern Media & Application Developer | Kweekvijver Noord

February 2015 - June 2015, Leeuwarden, The Netherlands

Internship at a creative company that develops websites, videos, documentaries, photos, animations, branding, applications and Virtual Reality solutions for various clients.

Tasks included:

- Creating creative solutions
- Contact with customers and getting to a solution
- Teamwork with people in different fields from Media & IT

· Farm Assistant | Common Ground Farm

July 2017 - August 2017, Saint Thomas, Ontario, Canada

Skills

Technical Skills

- Python, Java, C#
- Web Development (PHP, Javascript, CSS, Symfony, Yii2)
- Databases
- Algorithms & Data Structures
- Android Development
- Operating Systems (Linux, Windows)
- Networking and Security Security
- Docker, Virtualization
- Continuous Integration & Development

Languages

- Dutch (Native)
- West Frisian (Native)
- English (Professional Proficiency)
- Spanish (Limited Working Proficiency)

Organizational skills

- Excellent communication skills
- Team Leadership and management skills
- Professional presentation skills
- Documentation & Technical Writing

Honors & Awards

Finalist Skills Heroes

One of the finalists of the Skills Heroes 2016

The Skills Heroes is a professional competition for secondary vocational education in The Netherlands. Participants go through various qualification rounds and finally the national finals, participants compete in their field to become the best in the Netherlands.